SIMONA MADEDDU MBA

Junior Analyst

4 +4915259852062 **♥** Berlin, Germany

@ simomade@yahoo.it

@ linkedin.com/in/simona-madeddu

SUMMARY

Experienced Team Lead with a diverse industry background, including logistics, e-commerce, and online accommodation services. Skilled in Operations Management, Logistics, Root Cause Analysis, Management, and Report Writing. Recently completed an intensive Data Analytics Bootcamp at Le Wagon to enhance skills in data sourcing, extraction, transformation, and visualization. Familiar with tools like Google Sheets, SQL, Looker Studio, Power BI, and Python for Data Analytics

SKILLS

Coaching		CRM	Management		data analysis		_
Leadership		Programming		Python		Sheets	Tableau
Looker	P	ower Bl	Dbt	SQL			

PROJECTS

Key2Home

- **=** 06/2023 Q Le Wagon- online
- Data-driven identification of the best French areas for second home sales.
- Team of 5 created investor profiles and interactive dashboards for easy exploration and comparison
- •Used BigQuery, Google Colab, Python, dbt, Notion, and Tableau

AWARDS



Team of the 4th **Ouarter 2012- UPS**



The best CSAT team -**Booking.com Jun 2019 Best overall Team CSAT** score in the office

TRAINING / COURSES

Change Management

Booking.com

Coaching for success

Booking.com

Managing performance

Booking.com

Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Online Course -

Udemy

Managing people

Booking.com

Diversity and Inclusion

Paypal

Presentation skills

LIPS

Interview Skills

Paypal

EDUCATION

Data Analytics

Le Wagon

- **=** 04/2023 06/2023
- 9-week full-time intensive coding boot camp
- in-depth analysis of business data and building automated dashboards with Google Sheets

online

- worked with ELT tools, APIs, and No-code/Lowcode tools for data extraction and centralization
- used BigQuery, SQL for querying data, DBT to manage data workflows, and build data pipelines
- Practiced visualization and dashboarding with Looker Studio, Power Bl, and Tableau
- Run analysis on large volumes of data with
- Worked on a group project in a team of 5

MBA in Finance

Dublin Business School

MSc in Chemistry

Università degli Studi di Sassari

CERTIFICATION

Data Analytics

Le Wagon

EXPERIENCE

CS Guest Team Lead - CS Global operations

Booking.com

= 01/2015 - 04/2023 Perlin, Germany

Online accommodation services

- •Coached and guided a team of 15 toward improvement using effective communication and leadership skills.
 - •Experienced in fostering a productive and positive work environment
 - Demonstrated strong leadership by monitoring team quality, productivity, and performance, while motivating and inspiring team members.

TRAINING / COURSES

High Performance Teams

Booking.com

Managing within the law

Paypal

Advanced Communication Skills

Booking.com

LANGUAGES

English Proficient

Italian Native

EXPERIENCE

Customer solution Team Leader

E-commerce

- Performance reviews and coaching of a team of
- Identified and addresses performance gaps
- Empowered team members to reach their full
- Created a positive and supportive work environment

Operations, Billing & EA Collection Team Leader

= 08/2010 - 07/2014

O Dublin, Ireland

Logistics

- Managed a team of 5credit controllers, 5 self billing administrators and 2 operators
- Tracked key activities and measured departmental performance
- Identified training and development needs and managed rolling training programs.
- Established root cause analysis and communicated efficiently to appropriate department
- Interviewed temporary and permanent candidates

QC chemist

ALcontrol Dublin

= 04/2008 - 04/2009

O Dublin, Irelan

Laboratory services

- Developed and validated new methods in accordance with quality procedures
- Provided technical training and support to staff
- Evaluated, installed, and validated new instruments
- Investigated atypical results and quality system failure